all right so look at this let's have a
好吧，看看这个，让我们有一个
go with what we've got
跟着我们所拥有的
so this was gonna be a fairly demo heavy
所以这将是一个相当繁重的演示
presentation fortunately I have actually
演讲很幸运，我实际上
got some code snippets from the demo in
从演示中获得了一些代码片段
the slides so hopefully we should be
幻灯片，希望我们应该
able to at least talk about the sort of
至少可以谈论那种
things that I was going to do so if we
我要做的事情，如果我们
can switch over to my laptop later on
以后可以切换到我的笔记本电脑
then we will but if we can't then we'll
然后我们会，但是如果不能，那么我们会
just we'll make do so my name is Mike we
我们会尽力而为，所以我叫迈克
both work in the support team there and
都在那里的支持团队工作
this talk is titled baking a Java EE 8
这个演讲的标题是烘烤Java EE 8
micro PI it's it's had to change a
微型PI，必须更改
little bit from that due to did
一点点由于
completely different hardware issues
完全不同的硬件问题
before we even got here
在我们到达这里之前
so it's not many good talk for hardware
因此，对于硬件来说，这不是很多好话
gremlins though affecting what this is
gremlins虽然影响这是什么
about is putting Java e8 and Java in
关于将Java e8和Java放入
general into context so see given that
一般而言，因此请参阅
Java 8 has just been released there's
Java 8刚刚发布了
going to be tons of talk to Java 1 that
与Java 1进行大量讨论
are going to go into all the specs that
将进入所有规格
are going to tell you all about how they
会告诉大家他们如何
work so although we'll be touching on
工作，尽管我们会继续
that that's not the core motivation for
那不是
this talk the core thing that I'm
这是我最核心的话题
looking to do here is write a little bit
想要在这里做的就是写一点
of context show you kind of where Java 8
的上下文向您展示了Java 8在哪里
is now where it's been and how it
现在是它去过的地方以及如何
relates to the world that we're in
与我们所处的世界有关
currently yeah so let's get started such
目前是的，所以让我们开始吧
a little bit about me and Andre so I am
关于我和安德烈的一些事，所以我
a part of support team member that's my
我的支持团队成员的一部分
twitter handle if you want to follow me
如果你想跟我推特
and snowboarder and there's my proof
和滑雪板，这是我的证明
that that is a genuine photo of me but
那是我的真实照片，但是
it's it is made to look much better than
它看起来比
he actually is so Andre is also prior
他实际上是安德烈（Andre）
support that's him on Twitter and he's a
支持那是他在Twitter上，他是一个
dad and obviously doesn't have much time
爸爸，显然没有太多时间
for anything actually exciting anymore
对于任何真正令人兴奋的事情
since that happened
因为那件事发生了
so what's this all about then so the key
那么这是怎么回事，所以关键
thing that I want to talk about to begin
我想谈的事情开始
with is how lightweight Joffrey really
Joffrey到底有多轻巧
is so Joffrey traditionally I mean
从传统上讲，乔佛里就是这样
you'll know is have lots of lots of
你会知道有很多很多
criticism about how it's heavy weights
有关其重量如何的批评
bloated it's bulky it's all difficult to
ated肿它笨重，很难
work with I think to be honest I think
与我合作我认为我是诚实的
in general that the tide is turning on
总的来说，潮流正在加剧
that sort of opinion more and more
这种意见越来越多
people are using modern Joffrey in
人们在使用现代Joffrey
finding out that it's completely
发现它是完全
different to how it used to be so I
与过去不同
don't want to label that point too much
不想过多标记这一点
but just kind of investigate what makes
但只是调查是什么使
it lightweight why is why is it easy to
它很轻便，为什么容易
take it up and running with then I'm
拿起它并与我一起运行
gonna look out what's in Jerry eight
看看杰里八世有什么
today what's been released and what kind
今天发布了什么，什么样的
of things can you use and so that this
可以使用的东西，所以这
last point has been heavily modified so
最后一点已经过大量修改，因此
he would just recently found out that
他最近才发现
Java is moving to the Eclipse Foundation
Java正在迁移到Eclipse Foundation
and then it was announced that that
然后宣布
project was going to be named Eva J
该项目将被命名为Eva J
Eclipse Enterprise for Java but then
Eclipse Enterprise for Java，但随后
also there's been a recent clarification
最近也有澄清
from Michael link of itch from Eclipse
来自Eclipse的itch的Michael链接
to say that although EE for J is the
说尽管J的EE是
umbrella project name it's not
伞项目名称不是
necessarily going to be the replacement
必将成为替代品
branding for Java EE so I had to modify
Java EE的品牌，所以我不得不修改
a third time because we don't know what
第三次因为我们不知道是什么
the name for it is going to be we know
我们知道它的名字
that it's probably not going to be Java
可能不会是Java
EE due to just a trademark things via
EE由于只是商标而已
that there's a lot of reasons to be very
有很多原因
excited about the future of java re'
对Java re的未来感到兴奋
whatever it becomes and I'll touch on
不管它变成什么，我都会讲
that a little bit and also depending on
这一点，还取决于
how the demo works hopefully get a
演示如何进行，希望能得到一个
chance to look at that as well so when I
有机会看一下，所以当我
kick off with a bit of recent history so
从最近的历史开始
kind of around this time sort of four
大约在这一次的四个
years ago we had java re' seven just out
几年前，我们有7个Java
of the door with GlassFish for i am
GlassFish对我来说是门的
because i wasn't a java one but i was
因为我不是Java人，但是我是
back in the office blogging
回到办公室写博客
about it and trying to get everyone
关于它，并试图让每个人
excited about the new java re' 7 release
对新的Java re'7版本感到兴奋
and as I was preparing this presentation
当我准备这个演讲时
I was thinking a lot about the the
我在想很多
general landscape that we've got at the
我们在
moment the service that we've got
当下我们获得的服务
available how things have been changing
可用的情况如何变化
there's been a lot of change that's just
发生了很多变化
in recent months but trying to think
最近几个月，但试图思考
back to when GlassFish 4 first came out
回到GlassFish 4第一次问世的时候
actually was quite difficult so I went
其实很难，所以我去了
googling I went to have a look at where
谷歌搜索我去看看
things were where key technologies were
关键技术在哪里
and what I found that she kind of
我发现她有点
surprised me how far we've come in such
让我们感到惊讶的是，我们走了这么远
a short time so the first thing was
短时间，所以第一件事是
docker at this point was just three
码头工人此时只有三个
months old so Linux containers obviously
几个月大，所以Linux容器很明显
were a thing and people were aware of
是一件事情，人们意识到
them people was trying to use them but
他们人们试图使用它们，但是
docker was really really new so at the
码头工人真的很新，所以在
point when Java EE 7 was released this
Java EE 7发布的时间
whole you know brave new world of
整个你都知道勇敢的新世界
containers and you know shipping
集装箱，你知道运输
absolutely everything in just one night
一晚上绝对一切
neat nice neat little box that year
那年整齐漂亮
operations team can't mess with you know
运营团队不能惹你
that that was completely out of the
那完全超出了
heads of most people
大多数人的头
wasn't really on the roadmap
并不是真的在路线图上
wildfly it's one of Pyro's competitors
它是Pyro的竞争对手之一
that didn't exist in a named former it
它在一个命名的前者中不存在
was still JBoss AAS the open source
仍然是JBoss AAS的开源
version of JBoss
JBoss版本
so I put it was before spring boots
所以我把它放在春季靴子之前
actually at that date you can check on
实际上在那个日期你可以检查
github because that's how I find out
github，因为那是我发现的方式
there are lots of tags sort of
有很多标签
pre-release tags of spring boots so it
弹簧靴的预发布标签
was being very actively developed at
在
that point but it's I know I didn't go
那一点，但是我知道我没有去
into the details of what features they
深入了解他们具有哪些功能
got in there yet but it was still very
到达那里，但仍然非常
very early days quite far away from its
很早就离它很远
version one WebSphere Liberty profile in
的第一个版本的WebSphere Liberty概要文件
June 2013 had recently been released
最近发布了2013年6月
it's actually wasn't long after I had
其实我没多久
left IBM so I used to work for IBM a
离开了IBM，所以我曾经为IBM工作
little bit before this so I kind of saw
在这之前一点点，所以我有点看到
a little bit of the background of
一点点的背景
Liberty being created and that was
自由被创造，那是
something I was quite interested in but
我很感兴趣但是
at that point it was still very very
那时还是非常非常
early it was just implementing actually
早期它实际上只是在实施
the Java EE 6 specifications
Java EE 6规范
it was quite far away from doing in Java
这与用Java进行开发还差得很远
7 stuff it took me quite a while to
我花了相当长的时间才完成的7件事
adapt to those and a lot of the features
适应这些和很多功能
that are in WebSphere Liberty now were
现在在WebSphere Liberty中是
not in Liberty profile as it was so
不在自由概况中
bring this forward to four years later
将此推到四年后
we're now at a stage where Java EE 8 has
我们现在处于Java EE 8拥有的阶段
been released and obviously in that time
被释放，显然是在那个时候
docker is now the dominant container
码头工人现在是主要的容器
format so it's gone from completely
格式，所以它完全消失了
brand-new and a lot of people being the
崭新的，很多人
lowest skeptical about it it's gone you
对此持怀疑态度的人已经过去了
know through the traditional hype curve
通过传统的炒作曲线知道
and to be honest has not really been the
而且说实话并不是真的
the massive trough of disillusionment of
幻灭的巨大低谷
most things yet but when you look at
大多数事情，但是当你看着
competitors to docker like core OS who
像核心OS这样的docker的竞争对手
did their own container format even they
做了他们自己的容器格式，即使他们
in their engines will support Dockers
他们的引擎将支持Dockers
container format so a might still be a
容器格式，因此可能仍然是
little bit early to call it but it does
早一点叫它，但它确实
my doctor is probably one on the
我的医生可能是
container format Wars before they even
容器格式甚至比他们大战
started really but that has actually
确实开始了，但是实际上
introduced quite a seismic shift in just
引入了相当大的变化
the way that we deploy things in general
我们一般部署事物的方式
when you look at the really key
当你看着真正的关键
technologies in cloud computing at the
云计算技术
moment we've got kubernetes which is got
马上我们有了kubernetes
awkward is hot and lots of other things
尴尬很热，还有很多其他事情
which are only really exist because of
真正存在是因为
what docker has done why I've included a
码头工人做了什么，为什么我加入了一个
non Java technology there it's a while
非Java技术还有一段时间
fly first on has become what a flight
第一次飞行已成为一种飞行
they've I put down that they fully
他们把我完全放下
productized swarm so swarm is their
蜂拥而至的群体
composable job EE application server so
可组合的作业EE应用程序服务器
if you've not used it before you can
如果您还没使用过它
define fractions in swarm which are
定义群中的分数是
really small kind of components may be
很小的一种组件可能是
just like a CD on jax-rs and nothing
就像jax-rs上的CD一样，什么也没有
else they've got a microphone file
否则他们有一个麦克风文件
fraction as well I haven't said they've
我也没有说他们已经
released it because I'm not sure what
发布它是因为我不确定
had they stand on support as to know the
他们是否愿意支持以了解
wild flight is their unsupported you
野外飞行是他们不支持的你
know innovation stream it is now into a
知道创新流现在已经变成了
proper product remember when it first
正确的产品记住它什么时候第一次
came out it really did seem to me and
出来的确对我来说确实如此，
probably to quite a lot of other people
可能对很多其他人来说
as a bit of a hobby project it was quite
作为一个业余项目，这是相当
good when it worked it was quite easy to
它工作时很好，很容易
get wrong and break and quite hard to
弄错了，打破了，很难
find out where it broke but quite
找出破裂的地方，但相当
quickly Red Hat of put a lot of effort
红帽很快投入了很多心血
into that and made into a really really
变成一个真正的
good product and good compared for us
好的产品，对我们来说比较好
off your spring boot have been making
从你的春季靴一直
their jars not was it's just long enough
他们的罐子不是足够长
to stay for quite a few years now I
我现在待了好几年
think the key thing there really is that
认为真正关键的是
they've they were really the ones to
他们真的是那些
kick off the current kind of fat jar
开始当前的胖子罐
movement if you like so it's really
运动，如果你喜欢，那真的
popular I think mainly or the key
我认为主要是流行还是关键
benefit that I see is that you keep all
我看到的好处是你保留了所有
of your configuration within one waffle
一个华夫饼中的配置
within one distributable so rather than
在一个可分配范围内，而不是
having your application which you can
拥有您可以的应用程序
deploy to an application server but then
部署到应用服务器，然后
it won't run because you also need to
它不会运行，因为您还需要
get some configuration in the
在中获取一些配置
application server that's non-issue
非发行的应用程序服务器
whispering boot because it's all just
耳语的引导，因为这只是
packaged together which is nice
打包在一起很好
IBM a released open Liberty everyone
IBM一个开放的开放Liberty所有人
noticed that happened fairly recently if
注意到这是最近发生的，如果
you don't I BM have obviously got a
你不是我BM显然有一个
booth at the exhibition center you can
您可以在展览中心的摊位
go and find out about that I know a lot
去了解一下，我知道很多
the guys there are quite keen to chat
那里的家伙很想聊天
about that
关于那个
so open liberty is remember when
所以开放的自由是记得什么时候
websphere liberty was the the main thing
网络自由是最主要的
they were saying that I think about 40%
他们说我认为大约40％
of the server was open source so they've
服务器是开源的，所以他们已经
open source a lot more of the server
开源更多的服务器
it's not quite all of WebSphere Liberty
它不是WebSphere Liberty的全部
so a few things that are left out of
所以一些遗漏的东西
that so for instance the admin console
例如管理控制台
that they've got is not in the open
他们没有公开
source version but what is in there is
源代码版本，但是里面有
all of the Java EE specifications and
所有Java EE规范和
all of the micro profile specifications
所有微轮廓规范
that they've pushed out so as developers
他们已经推出，所以作为开发人员
who want to write applications to run on
谁想要编写运行应用程序
a server and just want something to run
一台服务器，只想运行一些东西
stuff that's that's a really great
真的很棒
option now and of course that's us
现在选择，当然就是我们
obviously we didn't exist four years ago
显然我们四年前不存在
but since then we've seen that GlassFish
但是从那以后我们就看到了GlassFish
is no longer commercially supported
不再受到商业支持
payara has brought in pirate server and
payara带来了海盗服务器，并且
we've also introduced PI our micro which
我们还介绍了PI micro
we'll be talking about today and finally
我们将在今天最后讨论
we've got the Eclipse micro profile we
我们有Eclipse微型配置文件
see show of hands who's not heard of
看到没有听说过的举手
micro profile ok so a few people haven't
微型个人资料好，所以有些人没有
heard it ok so I'll give you a bit of
没关系，所以我给你一点
background about what micro profile
关于什么微资料的背景
actually is then so it all kind of
其实就是这样
starts back last year around June and
从去年6月左右开始
it's been really a collaboration between
这实际上是
Red Hat IBM awesome payara
红帽IBM出色的Payara
Tommy tribe and a few of the Java
汤米部落和一些Java
community groups like the London Java
伦敦爪哇等社区团体
community and Su Java in Brazil and
社区和巴西的Su Java
effectively what it is is just it's a
实际上，这只是一个
response to the question that often gets
对经常遇到的问题的回应
thrown in Java EE about innovation so
引发Java EE创新
Java EE you might well know by design go
您可能设计精通的Java EE
slowly
慢慢地
it doesn't want to kind of push forward
它不想推进
and try and standardize on something
并尝试标准化某些东西
before it's a well-respected technology
才是受人尊敬的技术
because it has to be backwards
因为它必须向后
compatible it's got all these different
兼容，所有这些都不同
kind of business requirements
种业务要求
so because obviously that there's that
所以因为很明显
restriction of Java EE and we don't want
Java EE的限制，我们不想
to kind of break that all the guys
打破所有的家伙
involved in my profile and we a payara
参与了我的个人资料，我们为payara
were quite involved with that decided
参与了这个决定
that what we need really is a new place
我们真正需要的是一个新地方
where we can kind of sandbox new
我们可以在哪里找到新的沙箱
technologies that react to what's
对什么做出反应的技术
actually going on out in the real world
实际发生在现实世界中
get some quick feedback from from you
从您那里获得一些快速反馈
guys developers who want to use this
想要使用此功能的开发人员
kind of thing and these API is and then
这类东西，然后这些API
hopefully use that as a way to kind of
希望以此作为一种方式
push forward into Java EE
推进Java EE
it's obviously was announced as an
它显然是宣布为
initiative in June last year we
去年六月的倡议
announced microvolt 1.0 which was really
宣布了微伏特1.0，这真的
just a starting point based on Java EE 7
只是基于Java EE 7的起点
api's just CDI jax-rs and JSONP just
api只是CDI jax-rs和JSONP
last year at JavaOne the reason why we
去年在JavaOne的原因
only went for those was because we
只是去那些是因为我们
wanted to stick it right back to the
想把它粘回去
absolute bare minimum that you would
绝对的最低要求
need to write a micro service style
需要写一个微服务风格
application in today's world so we
在当今世界的应用，所以我们
accept that you would likely have to add
接受您可能必须添加
the extra on top of it we wanted to
我们想要的最重要的是
start with as little as possible so that
尽可能少地开始
we didn't add too much extra cruft that
我们没有添加太多多余的东西
we regretted down the line that's
我们很遗憾
progressed quite a lot since then so
从那以后进步很大
we've released 1.1 I think 1.2 is as
我们发布了1.1，我认为1.2是
I've been released there okay so it's
我已经被释放在那里了，所以
sort of released for 1.2 I think there
我认为那里发布了1.2
still needs to be a few after things
仍然需要一些事
need to be tied off before we properly
我们需要绑扎好
announce it but we've got an API for
宣布它，但我们有一个API
configuration which I actually show a
我实际上显示的配置
little bit in this slide deck we've got
在这个幻灯片中，我们有一点
an API in 1.2 for metrics for health
1.2中用于健康指标的API
checks for JWT token propagation and I
检查JWT令牌传播，我
think code everything I think that's
想代码一切我认为那是
everything that there's been an update
一切都有更新
to the config API as well and
以及config API
fault-tolerance
容错
yes we've got an 8 an API fer fault
是的，我们有8个API错误
tolerance in micro services as well so
微服务的容忍度也是如此
or sinjar v8 again I didn't want to kind
还是sinjar v8，我不想友善
of come
的来
ignore all the stuff that's in it we've
忽略其中的所有内容
got a few things that have been upgrades
有一些已经升级的东西
jax-rs has now got a reactive client in
jax-rs现在有一个响应式客户端
it just had to cry for quite a while but
它只哭了好一阵子，但是
there's no reactive api's to work with
没有可使用的反应式API
that there's also server sent events in
还有服务器发送的事件
jax-rs which I think have been out in or
我认为已经存在的jax-rs或
standardized in kind of the non Java
非Java标准化
sphere for quite a while so now we've
球体了很长一段时间，所以现在我们已经
got standard in jax-rs certainly for
在jax-rs中肯定有标准
which I think it's actually one of the
我认为这实际上是其中之一
really really major things in this
真的很重要
release I know servlet is a very old
发布我知道servlet很老了
technology but that now supports 80 to
技术，但现在支持80到
be - if you thinking well that's fine
是-如果您想的很好，那很好
h-2b - or is a big thing you really need
h-2b-或您确实需要做的一件大事
to look into it I really think that's
调查一下，我真的认为这是
going to be a major major thing over the
将成为主要的重大事情
next few years particularly with the
未来几年，尤其是
speed improvements it brings and the
带来的速度改进和
security by default that it brings you
默认情况下会带来安全性
can't run actually to be - without being
不能真实地运行-没有被
secure I could talk a little bit about
确保我可以谈一点
that later but I don't want to labour
那晚，但我不想工作
that too much
太多了
I've been validation 2.0 is out it's got
我一直在验证2.0已经完成了
quite a few updates in that same with
在与相同的很多更新
JSF I don't there's anything any
JSF我什么都没有
individual thing that's to major in JSF
在JSF中主要涉及的个别事情
I know it does support WebSockets now
我知道它现在支持WebSockets
natively so you don't have to add in
本机的，所以您不必添加
your own framework like atmosphere or
您自己的框架，例如气氛或
something it's all native CDI - brings
都是本地CDI的东西-带来
asynchronous events and JSONP brings a
异步事件和JSONP带来了
few kind minor additions I think I merge
我认为我合并了一些小小的补充
patch and Jason pointer just to you know
补丁和杰森指针，只是你知道
close off a few things that were missing
关闭一些缺少的东西
really from the first back new specs
确实是从最初的新规格开始
we've got jari security it's kind of
我们有jari安全性
based on jaws pick I don't know I'm very
基于下巴选择我不知道我非常
pleased you have to speak about that a
很高兴你不得不谈论一个
bit more if you want
如果你想多一点
but uh nothing much room should be on
但是应该没有多少空间
there yeah can you hear me the the thing
是的，你能听到我的意思吗
is with it with security it's uh it's a
具有安全性，它是一个
crucial component of Java EE and and
Java EE的关键组件以及
business applications but it was
商业应用程序，但是
traditionally hard to set up security
传统上很难设置安全性
and was divided or between the
并且被划分或之间
application and the application server
应用程序和应用程序服务器
so traditionally specify how users
因此传统上指定用户
credentials are authorized but how the
凭据被授权，但是如何
user is authenticated and given the
用户通过身份验证并获得
roles is specifying the server and the
角色指定服务器和
application only consumes this
应用程序仅消耗此
information specifies required roles but
信息指定了所需角色，但
it's cancer or it couldn't influence how
是癌症还是无法影响
the user is authenticated and authorized
用户已通过身份验证和授权
and that was an addition I think even
我认为这是一个补充
Java is six supported this that's it
Java支持六种，仅此而已
there's a specification called a spec
有一个规范叫做规范
which provides a way how to plug in your
这提供了一种方法来插入您的
authorization mechanism from application
应用程序的授权机制
but this there are too many problems one
但是这个问题太多了
obvious problem is that very few people
明显的问题是很少有人
know about it as there are other
知道它，因为还有其他
specifications in Java EE version which
Java EE版本中的规范
are also lesser-known and this is
也鲜为人知，这是
probably the least known specification
可能是鲜为人知的规范
and the other point why it also isn't so
还有一点为什么它也不是这样
widely adopted and known is that it's
被广泛采用和众所周知的是
very complicated it has like three
非常复杂，就像三个
different interfaces but you need to
不同的界面，但您需要
combine together and and if I could
结合在一起，如果可以的话
compare it to the new Java security API
将其与新的Java安全性API进行比较
it's like in jb2 and a type III so the
就像在jb2和III型中一样
the just peek was really complex to work
只是偷看工作真的很复杂
with and the music security API is based
和音乐安全性API是基于
on the CDI and only with the fever
在CDI上并且只有发烧
rotations you can specify your own
您可以指定自己的轮换
pluggable module which you can put into
可插入的可插入模块
your application so you can account for
您的应用程序，以便您可以考虑
authentication and authorization from
来自的认证和授权
within your application and you no
在您的应用程序中，而您没有
longer need to
不再需要
depend on the configuration provided by
取决于提供的配置
the application server so the simplicity
应用服务器如此简单
was in mind there thanks Andre it was
想到那里谢谢安德烈
great to have someone else here she
很高兴在这里有其他人
knows what they're talking about to get
知道他们在说什么
some extra details see I think that that
一些额外的细节，我认为
kind of ties into what we saw on the
与我们在
previous slide about how the Java EE
关于Java EE的上一张幻灯片
landscape has changed and how we've got
景观已经改变，我们如何
spring boots and I should waffle ice
春季靴子，我应该胡扯冰
form and pie or a micro or which allow
形式和馅饼或微或允许
you to add configuration for your
您为您的配置添加配置
application server into the deployment
应用服务器进入部署
artifact so again like Java security is
工件，因此再次像Java安全性一样
kind of enabled a big thing about that
在某种程度上使这件事变得重要
as well Jason B is obviously and I
以及Jason B显然是我
always think there's a bit of a danger
总是以为有危险
of seen Jason being is quite a minor
杰森（Jason）的身材相当小
thing I think it's actually much more
我认为实际上更多
significant than people might think
比人们想象的重要
certainly from using it in in the demo
当然可以在演示中使用它
which I hope will melt actually look at
我希望它将融化
its it was quite significant and I think
它非常重要，我认为
it's it's a big help it's a lot of
这是很大的帮助，很多
convenience annotations but it will make
方便注释，但它将使
life a lot easier so when when we get to
生活要容易得多，所以当我们
the demo hopefully we will we're gonna
演示希望我们会
be running this on pyre on micro so just
在micro上用柴堆运行
wanted to for the benefit of people who
想要造福于那些
may not know about PI or micro and what
可能不知道PI或micro以及什么
that is go over a little bit about
那是关于
what's actually in it and what what we
里面到底有什么，我们有什么
do with it
用它做
so it's a downloadable jar artifact it's
所以这是一个可下载的jar工件
just 60 megabytes ish I think it's it
仅仅60兆字节就可以了
always tends to come up around 60
总是趋向于大约60
megabytes it's kind of varies a little
兆字节有点不同
bit from release to release based
从发布到发布
dynamically scalable so at its heart
动态可扩展，因此从本质上讲
it's got hazel cast and obviously hazel
它有淡褐色，很明显淡褐色
cast is really good at dynamically
演员真的很擅长动态
clustering with other different
与其他不同的聚类
environments so if you stand at one pile
环境，所以如果你站成一堆
on micro just you Java - jar player
在Micro上只是Java-jar播放器
might create a jar and then you stand up
可能会创建一个罐子，然后您站起来
another one they will automatically
他们会自动另一个
discover and cluster each other without
彼此发现并聚在一起
any extra effort on your part and
您需要付出额外的努力，并且
obvious because we're based on hazel
很明显，因为我们基于淡褐色
caste we've got all of the different
种姓，我们拥有所有不同的
kind of hazel cast plugins for
一种榛子演员插件
things like AWS deployments so it's got
像AWS部署这样的事情
native discovery Aveda other instances
本机发现Aveda其他实例
that run on AWS it can do it over TCP or
在AWS上运行的它可以通过TCP或
of a multicast it can use kubernetes as
多播可以使用kubernetes作为
your as well I think there's a few other
你也是，我想还有其他一些
different discovery methods as well that
以及不同的发现方法
can be added through plugins it's fully
可以通过插件完全添加
embeddable so you can just embed it to
可嵌入的，因此您可以将其嵌入
your application we call it web profile
您的应用程序，我们称其为Web个人资料
plus because it provides or it will
加号，因为它提供或它将
support all the same API as the java re'
支持与Java re'相同的所有API
web profile but one or two extra ones as
网页个人资料，但另外一两个
well they've been added in and it's all
好吧，它们已经被添加进来了
maven central there so I'm not sure if
那里的Maven中心，所以我不确定
that beta one snapshot is actually up
Beta 1快照实际上已启动
yet it was supposedly up around about
但据称它大约在
now I haven't actually been in touch
现在我实际上并没有联系
with that developers to see if it's been
与开发人员一起查看是否
released yet but there is definitely an
发布了，但肯定有一个
alpha 2 snapshot which is on the maven
Maven上的alpha 2快照
snapshots repository it's they're just
快照存储库
the key API so I won't go through them
关键的API，所以我不会通过它们
all but we can see that that's all
所有，但我们可以看到仅此而已
basically the web profile except for
基本上是网站配置文件，除了
we've added J batch we've added
我们添加了J批处理
concurrency and J cache which obviously
并发和J缓存，这显然
isn't a jari api yet it's still a
不是jari API，但仍然是
candidate to be one I think it should be
我认为应该成为一个候选人
but it's does need to be moving forward
但这确实需要向前发展
although the spec itself is still
虽然规范本身仍然
evolving we've also quite recently added
不断发展，我们最近还添加了
JCA to this so it's not been a prob
JCA为此，它不是一个问题
possible with web profile before what
可以使用网络配置文件之前的内容
that enables you to do is use it as a
使您能够做的就是将其用作
JMS client which i think is a really
我认为这是一个真正的JMS客户端
important thing for cloud native
对于云原生而言重要的事情
deployments but also it's meant that we
部署，但这也意味着我们
can create our own resource archives for
可以创建我们自己的资源档案
working with modern messaging
使用现代消息传递
communication tools like mqtt Apache
像mqtt Apache这样的通讯工具
Kafka Amazon's sqs service we actually
Kafka Amazon的sqs服务我们实际上
got a repository in github called our
在github中有一个名为我们的存储库
cloud connectors repository where we've
云连接器存储库
got examples of all of those say it is
所有这些的例子都说
very simple to use just kind of create a
使用起来非常简单，只是创建一个
new MDB use all the same activation
新的MDB使用相同的激活
conflict property and
冲突财产和
patience to set up your location for
耐心为您设置位置
your MQTT broker and you can subscribe
您的MQTT经纪人，您可以订阅
to messages just with normal MDB stuff
只是带有普通MDB内容的消息
so yeah EJB pool configurations can can
所以是的，EJB池配置可以
be used to control that the other thing
用来控制另一件事
is config that's the micro profile
是配置，这是微型配置文件
config api and that's been added for a
config api，并且已经为
little while now
不久
I think we've we certainly got a few
我想我们肯定有一些
extra updates for config 1.1 and i think
配置1.1的额外更新，我认为
that's due out in November ish time in
那是十一月的时间
our next release so that leads us onto
我们的下一个版本，使我们进入
the demo which is ready to switch over
准备切换的演示
to the laptops is that is that gonna
对笔记本电脑来说就是那样
happen let me get that sorted number 5
碰巧让我得到排序的数字5
to make sure I've got lucky
确保我很幸运
great you got something nope
太好了，你没有东西
there you go no that's nice
那你去不行那太好了
someone's like this
有人是这样的
so we'll have a go and see if we can get
所以我们去看看是否可以得到
everything up and running if not then I
如果没有一切，一切就开始运转了
can just talk you through things I guess
可以跟你讲讲我猜的事情
yes the best issues that it's not
是的，不是的最好的问题
detecting any input it did first thing
检测任何输入它做的第一件事
this morning but yes since not be able
今天早上，但是可以，因为不能
to get it since all right then
从那时开始就得到它
okay so let's ignore the demo then let's
好吧，让我们忽略该演示，然后让我们
go
走
okay so let's show you what the demo was
好的，让我们向您展示什么是演示
he was going to be running on my love of
他将要依靠我的爱
Raspberry Pi cluster there so the
树莓派集群在那里
cluster itself is just for the benefit
集群本身只是为了利益
of any hardware hackers in the room just
房间里的任何硬件黑客
a Raspberry Pi 3 on the bottom the red
底部的Raspberry Pi 3红色
board on the top and it's kind of it
在上面的板子，这是一种
looks like it's plugged into itself it's
看起来像是插入了它本身
not that's just transporting power from
不只是从那里输送电力
the main board that is a just a board
只是一个主板的主板
which kind of supports power for the 4
哪种支持4
ratified zeroes on top which allows it
批准的零在上面允许
to cluster together which worked
聚集在一起工作
beautifully back at home and then I
漂亮地回到家里，然后我
killed it because the problem with it is
杀了它，因为它的问题是
it's all coming through a single power
全部来自单一力量
source and the the issue with that is
来源，问题在于
that when you got all four them running
当你让他们四个都跑的时候
at once plus the main board there's not
一次加上主板没有
a lot of power to go around and it's
有很多力量可以绕过去
just slows down a lot so I tried to
只是减慢了很多，所以我试图
increase the pattern yeah don't mess
增加模式是的，不要乱
around with power and things like that
充满力量和类似的东西
when you don't know what you're doing so
当你不知道自己在做什么时
the demo scenario was gonna be all about
演示场景将是关于
dock it's based on a an application that
停靠它基于一个应用程序
we'd already got I guess stock ticker
我们已经猜到了股票行情
demo where we'd had a couple of Ralphie
演示中我们有几个Ralphie
PI's we stand up pyre on micro on one
PI是我们在微机上站得住脚的工具
which has got a stock ticker in it and
里面有股票行情自动收录器，
we stand the pile marker in a second one
我们将桩标放在第二个
which has got a web application and we
其中有一个网络应用程序，我们
use an EJB timer to fire events over CDI
使用EJB计时器通过CDI触发事件
which then because we've got hazel
那是因为我们有淡褐色
castor cluster these two together
脚轮将这两个群集在一起
rather than these events living just
而不是仅仅发生这些事件
within the first JVM these can be sent
这些可以在第一个JVM中发送
over the network to the other JVM and be
通过网络连接到另一个JVM并成为
processed by another member of the node
由节点的另一个成员处理
it's quite a neat API that we've got in
这是我们提供的一个非常简洁的API
PI or micro it's the same CDI events API
PI或Micro都是相同的CDI事件API
that you would normally use but we just
您通常会使用的，但我们只是
annotate that with at outbound so that's
用出站注释，这是
roughly what it was going to be so we've
大概会是什么，所以我们已经
got stock tickers at the bottom and
在底部显示股票行情
we've also got another feature in payara
我们在payara中还有另一个功能
which allows you to have clustered
这使您可以聚类
Singleton's this basically means that
Singleton的基本意思是
across the entire cluster you can stand
在整个集群中，您可以站立
up the same micro-service that you want
建立您想要的相同微服务
but you can guarantee that across the
但您可以保证
entire cluster there will only ever be
整个集群永远不会
one instance of that either EJB or annex
该EJB或附件的一个实例
actually completely feature yet but soon
实际上完全功能，但很快
to be and applicate a clustered scoped
成为并应用集群范围
CDI beam
CDI光束
so yes the stock ticker has any heavy
所以是的股票行情自动收录器
timer in it which is a singleton that'll
在其中的计时器是一个单例
produce events the stock web obviously
产生事件，股票网站明显
being on clustered together will receive
聚集在一起将收到
those events and push them through
这些事件并推动它们通过
WebSockets to a browser so they can be
WebSockets到浏览器，以便它们可以
consumed so I might have to skip through
消耗掉了，所以我可能不得不跳过
a little bit about the things that were
关于那件事的一点点
going to show but effectively what I
要显示但有效地我
would have shown an atty all this is on
会显示出所有这些
github so I could just see if I can get
github，所以我可以看看是否可以
that up
那个
at least be able to talk about the code
至少能够谈论代码
a bit she's better than that
她比那更好
great so
太好了
it's the first thing is how the stock
首先是库存如何
object so this is a stock Lib hopefully
对象，所以希望这是一个库存库
this has got the sets a little bit
这有一些设置
better it looks like it's good so
更好，看起来很好
actually this is gonna have all of the
实际上，这将拥有所有
kind of finished final stuff so I was
完成了一些最终的东西，所以我
going to kind of run through it and
要通过它来运行
write all the code for this but we just
为此编写所有代码，但我们只是
look at the the end product here so what
看看这里的最终产品
got is just a normal stock object I've
得到的只是我的普通库存对象
added JSONP annotations already but
已经添加了JSONP注释，但是
there's later so all we've got in our
后来，所以我们拥有的一切
stock object is a symbol a description
股票对象是符号说明
and a price
和一个价格
so this the symbol obviously every stock
所以这个符号显然是每只股票
needs to have a symbol that it
需要有一个标志，它
identifies itself with which needs to be
标识自己需要与之
unique price now this is just a a random
现在唯一的价格只是一个随机
double and a description which is a
双重和描述是
string so to begin with I created a to
字符串，因此我首先创建了一个
jason method which obviously just see
杰森方法，显然只是看到
related to adjacent object for me and
与我相邻的物体有关
then had a string which just two string
然后有一个字符串，只有两个字符串
method which just called that and then a
刚刚调用的方法，然后
two string on the data object that was
数据对象上的两个字符串
returned this was the kind of the old
返回这是旧的那种
java re' seven way of doing things with
Java re'的七种处理方式
the JSONP api so it it's quite
JSONP api，所以相当
functional I mean that there's not a lot
功能性我的意思是没有太多
there that's really difficult or hard to
那真的很难还是很难
use or but it is quite manual so kind of
使用or，但它是相当手动的，所以
creating all this stuff is involves a
创建所有这些东西涉及
lot of extra work from I think so the
我认为还有很多额外的工作
other thing that we need once we've got
一旦获得，我们需要的其他东西
our stock object is the stock ticker to
我们的库存对象是股票行情
actually set the stock price so we've
实际上设定了股票价格，所以我们已经
obviously the the object is just there
显然，对象就在那里
it's not doing anything at the moment
目前没有做任何事情
yes here we can see that we've got a
是的，在这里我们可以看到我们有一个
stock ticker all it is is just a
股票行情记录只是一个
singleton EJB with an EJB timer there
带有EJB计时器的单例EJB
which is scheduled for every second you
预定您每秒
can see at the top I've added the
可以在顶部看到我已经添加了
clustered annotation there which is pyro
在那里的聚簇注释是pyro
micro annotation just to ensure a single
微注解只是为了确保单个
instance across the entire cluster
整个集群中的实例
probably it's probably a bit better yes
可能会更好一点
so we've got this event here that I've
所以我们在这里有这个活动
created here I've annotated with inject
在这里创建的我已注解
and at outbound so the outbound
在出站，所以出站
annotation if it tells the clustered CDI
注释是否告诉群集的CDI
event bus that these events need to go
这些事件需要去的事件总线
across the network to anything else
跨网络到其他任何地方
that's that's cluster than that's
那是那个集群，而不是那个
listening on them and see that in the
听他们的话，然后在
brackets here also added loopback equals
括号在这里还添加了回送等于
true now the reason for that is that if
是的，现在的原因是，如果
you want to process the events within
您想要处理其中的事件
the same JVM as well as over the network
相同的JVM以及通过网络
then we add the loop back so that it
然后我们将循环添加回去
sends it to itself as well you don't do
也可以将其发送给自己
that by default and here obviously in
默认情况下，这里显然
the timer were just kind of creating it
计时器只是一种创造
a new generic instance of stock with
一个新的通用股票实例
just a math or random for the yet for
只是数学或随机
the actual stock price which obviously
实际股价显然
means that the yep
是的，是的
every note yes yes it's what we cannot
每一个音符是的是我们无法做到的
actually also do is that there's another
实际上也做的是
thing that we can do in the brackets
我们可以做的事情
there is add a name to the event and
有一个名称添加到事件和
then when you add your inbound
然后当您添加入站时
annotation you can specify that you only
注释，您可以指定仅
want to listen to a certain name so it
想听一个名字，所以
effectively worked it's not quite a
有效地工作它不是一个
topic style of thing but it's
事情的主题风格，但这是
effectively doing the same sort of thing
有效地做同样的事情
yes yes entendre just point out that
是的，参与者只是指出
yellow with CDI events you kind of
带有CDI事件的黄色
filter by the object class type okay so
按对象类类型过滤好吧
yes so we've got the stock ticker that
是的，所以我们有股票报价器
set the stock price and we've got a
设定股票价格，我们有一个
publisher for the CDI event bus so if
CDI事件总线的发布者，因此如果
the stock web listener what we're doing
股票网络监听器我们在做什么
is creating a WebSocket
正在创建一个WebSocket
endpoint which is just a standard API
端点，这只是一个标准的API
that's been around in in Java EE 7 so at
在Java EE 7中已经存在
this point in the demo all we're using
演示中的这一点，我们正在使用
is just Java EE 7 stuff in existing
只是现有的Java EE 7
technologies so we're gonna kind of
技术，所以我们会
start there and then add on the Java EE
从那里开始，然后在Java EE上添加
stuff later so we need to class to
东西，所以我们需要分类
manage the WebSocket sessions and then
管理WebSocket会话，然后
for each session that's registered we're
对于每个注册的会话，我们
going to kind of push things out via the
会通过
on message I think and then class to
在我认为的消息上，然后上课
listen for the stock events on the CD
收听CD上的库存事件
event bus
事件总线
[Music]
[音乐]
so first we've got the session manager
所以首先我们有会议经理
which is an application scoped CDI bean
这是应用程序范围内的CDI bean
and we inject the CDI event bus itself
然后注入CDI事件总线本身
this is how we actually receive the
这就是我们实际上收到的方式
events that we've got you've got a
我们所拥有的事件
registration do you register session
注册你注册会议吗
which is just a hash set and here we've
这只是一个哈希集，我们在这里
got an observer method where we've added
我们添加了一个观察者方法
our at observes at inbound stock so the
我们在观察库存
only thing that we've really added there
我们真正添加到那里的唯一一件事
is the at inbound and there that's where
是入站，在那里
you put the extra you know in the
你把你知道的多余的东西放在
brackets to filter by that the name in
括号以按名称过滤
the the for each loop that we've got
我们得到的每个循环
there as well each session that we've
那里的每个环节
got registered we wait for the event to
已注册，我们等待事件发生
be received as soon as it's received it
收到后立即收到
will send everything out to every
将一切发送给每个人
subscribed consumer that's all this is
订阅的消费者就是这些
kind of fairly basic just send in text
有点基本的只是发送文本
as a string object if I you know to here
作为字符串对象（如果我知道的话）
let's have a look at the actual
让我们看看实际
WebSocket class
WebSocket类
so we've got the server end point of
所以我们有服务器端
slash graph we're injecting the session
斜线图，我们正在注入会话
manager that we just created got unopen
我们刚刚创建的经理未打开
method here which registers the session
在此注册会话的方法
then once it's registered then we let
然后一旦注册，我们就让
the session manager push out all the
会话管理器将所有
data based on the observe method so
基于观察方法的数据
that's really all what's going on there
这就是那里发生的一切
I won't go into the the actual
我不会去实际的
JavaScript page because it's just a
JavaScript页面，因为它只是一个
JavaScript page which has the JavaScript
具有JavaScript的JavaScript页面
WebSocket endpoints to to listen on
WebSocket端点监听
those so now there we should be at the
那些，所以现在我们应该在
point where everything that we've got at
指出我们所拥有的一切
the moment if I was able to run it in a
如果我能够在一个
show you're working we would have a
表明你在工作，我们会有一个
single JVM with the stock ticker every
每个股票行情自动收录器的单个JVM
second that's going to publish events
第二个将发布事件
those are going to be fired out and then
这些将被解雇，然后
received by the other instance and then
被另一个实例接收，然后
that's going to be pushing these things
这将推动这些事情
out via WebSockets and via the session
通过WebSockets和会话退出
manager to the browser so what the user
浏览器的管理员，那么用户
sees is a nice dynamic graph which just
看到的是一个很好的动态图
has WebSockets dynamically updating
具有WebSockets动态更新
everything so at the moment that's
一切都在那一刻
something that you can do well before
你可以做得很好的事情
today before Java EE 8 came out and
在Java EE 8发布之前的今天，
there was nothing particularly new in
没有什么特别新的
there so my first thought for this like
在那里，所以我首先想到的是
I said at the beginning I wanted to put
我说一开始我想放
Java 8 into a little bit of context so I
Java 8进入了一点上下文，所以我
thought that the the issue with using
以为使用问题
the cd-i event bus although it's
cd-i事件总线，尽管它是
fantastic if you've got like an internal
如果你有一个内部的，那就太棒了
application where you control all of the
您可以控制所有应用程序的应用程序
services to you know give you your end
您所知道的服务会给您带来终点
application you can use the CDI event
您可以使用CDI事件的应用程序
bus for your internal communications
内部通讯总线
there you can use it wider than that if
在那里，您可以使用的范围比
you want but you can't guarantee there's
你想要，但你不能保证有
someone else who wants to maybe use one
想要使用一个的其他人
of your mic Riserva TSA's or if you want
您的麦克风Riserva TSA的麦克风，还是您想要的
to expose something publicly you can't
公开露面，你不能
actually guarantee that they're going to
真正保证他们会
be able to consume those sorts of events
能够消耗这类事件
so we need something else to handle that
所以我们需要别的东西来处理
and the solution there was server sent
和解决方案有服务器发送
events from Jackson RS softly I did have
我确实有来自Jackson RS的事件
the WebSockets thing already set up in
WebSockets已经设置好了
the stock web obviously we could have
股票网站显然我们可以拥有
used that but the the difference there
用那个，但那里的区别
is that WebSockets is binary
WebSockets是二进制的吗？
communicators two-way communication so
传播者双向交流所以
what you basically do is opening up a
你基本上要做的是开放一个
channel where you not only send dates
您不仅发送日期的渠道
but yours are waiting to receive data as
但您正在等待接收数据
well so you've got all these extra
好，所以您拥有了所有这些额外功能
endpoints listening for stuff that
端点监听那些
aren't doing anything because all we
什么也没做，因为我们
doing is broadcast so service and events
这样做是广播，所以服务和事件
is a perfect chance for this it's it's
这是一个绝好的机会，因为
just using rest it's using standard web
只是使用其余部分，而是使用标准网络
technologies that have been around for a
已经存在的技术
long time and there's basically designed
时间长了，基本上已经设计好了
for broadcast and so the other thing
广播等等
that I was going to do as well is again
我本来也会做的
assuming that we're going to make this
假设我们要做这个
thing public for other people to consume
供其他人消费的公共物品
we'll use JSON be to serialize the stock
我们将使用JSON be序列化股票
object and give like a nice a nice kind
反对，给人一种很好的一种
of stock object which we can then the
库存对象，然后我们可以
use easily by other consumers so this is
其他消费者容易使用，所以这是
actually where I cut code in the in the
其实我在
slides which makes things a lot easier
幻灯片使事情变得容易得多
so beginning with we saw this in github
所以首先我们在github上看到了
already this was the original way that I
这已经是我的原始方式
was doing things with JSONP so all we've
用JSONP做事，所以我们所做的一切
got is just a JSON object returned by it
得到的只是它返回的JSON对象
adjacent method and then we're just
相邻方法，然后我们就
saying that to string just fine but it's
说串就好了，但是
it's a little bit manual and bit brittle
这有点手动，有点脆
so these are the things that Jason B
这些就是Jason B
brings with it Jason B dotnet has got
带来了Jason B dotnet
quite a few examples and things and link
相当多的例子，事物和链接
to the specification and have been
符合规范，并且已经
affected we can see down at the bottom
受影响的我们可以在底部看到
there we've got this sort of stock
那里我们有这种存货
equals jason build it or create dot from
等于jason构建它或从中创建点
jason and i'll sorry that yeah that's to
杰森，对不起，那是为了
deserialize so that the one just above
反序列化，以便上面的一个
that is the the two string method just
那就是两个字符串的方法而已
here so what we're doing here is we've
在这里，所以我们在这里做的是
got jason be config which is move called
有杰森被配置，这就是所谓的移动
nillable config because we're
可配置，因为我们
for null values here what I've done is
对于空值，我所做的是
just put that in the brackets where I've
只是把它放在我已经
got doc create nillable config you don't
有文档创建您不想要的可配置
have to have that they can do dot create
必须有他们可以做点创建
with nothing in the brackets and it will
括号内没有任何东西，它将
just follow its own defaults rules to
只需遵循自己的默认规则即可
create the jason and it will just
创建杰森，它只会
serialize for you in the middle there
在中间为您序列化
we've got on our three three fields
我们已经进入了三个领域
we've got symbol which i've just left uh
我们有象征我刚刚离开了
nana Tate 'add I've put Jason be
娜娜·泰特（Nana Tate），“我把杰森（Jason）
transient on the string description
字符串描述上的瞬态
since just to demonstrate that we might
因为只是为了证明我们可能
have like quite a long or quite a heavy
喜欢很长很重
data field that we don't want to
我们不想的数据字段
serialize or it might be maybe an image
序列化或可能是图像
or something in your class that you
或你班上的东西
don't want to see a lot of - Jason Jason
不想看到很多-Jason Jason
be transient we'll just set that to be
是短暂的，我们将其设置为
ignored we've also got a Jason B
忽略了，我们还有Jason B
property there so again because this is
再次出现在那儿，因为这是
liturgist in each every time a
每一次的礼仪
generating random numbers and it's a
生成随机数，这是一个
stock ticker thought it's probably good
股票报价器认为这可能很好
to let people know that this isn't an
让人们知道这不是
actual stock price it is just a random
实际股价只是随机的
number so that will just override the
数字，这样就可以覆盖
actual price and that will mean that in
实际价格，这意味着
the json object that you get back that's
您返回的json对象是
what gets picked up there and i've seen
那里捡到什么，我已经看到
in the demo we needed to change our
在演示中，我们需要更改我们的
javascript class to from looking for the
javascript类，从寻找
dot price to look into dot random price
点价调查点随机价格
actually always that would not be found
实际上总是找不到
so move on so I'm gonna ask Andre to
所以继续前进，我要问安德烈
again come up and talk a little bit
再来一点
about the jax-rs reactive client API so
关于jax-rs反应式客户端API，所以
this wasn't something that I actually
这不是我真正的东西
included in my own demo but I thought it
包含在我自己的演示中，但我认为
was actually quite a significant feature
实际上是一个重要的功能
of jax-rs so I wanted to mention it
jax-rs，所以我想提一提
fortunately Alex tdum who is here and
幸运的是，Alex tdum在这里和
doing some of their own talks do go and
自己做一些演讲，然后
catch them if you can this is a very
如果可以的话赶上他们，这是一个非常
good speaker
好的演讲者
I'm sure his demos always work he's
我敢肯定他的演示总是奏效的
written this blog post which is very
写了这篇博客，这是非常
good investigation into things and he
很好地调查事物，他
goes over a little bit about the
谈到了一些
reactive client API just here so the
反应性客户端API就在这里，所以
reactive client API is like improvement
反应式客户端API就像改进一样
of the API with that's that was there
API的存在
already with Java EE 7 and it was called
已经在Java EE 7中被使用
a synchronous client API and it was
同步客户端API，
based on the Java 7 it couldn't use
基于无法使用的Java 7
completable future or not all these new
可完成的未来或不是所有这些新事物
stuff in java 8 like lambdas so it
Java 8中的东西像lambdas这样
provided more cumbersome API then it can
提供了更多麻烦的API，那么它可以
with Java 8 but previously with video
使用Java 8，但以前使用视频
synchronous API you had an option to
同步API，您可以选择
provide a callback when when you send a
发送回调时提供回调
get request to the service and the call
获取对服务和电话的请求
wouldn't be blocked so you can continue
不会被阻止，因此您可以继续
doing some other computations in the
在进行其他一些计算
same threat and then when the service
同样的威胁，然后当服务
call was finished the the application
通话完成了申请
server would execute the callback
服务器将执行回调
usually in a different thread and
通常在不同的线程中
without blocking your original threads
不会阻塞您的原始线程
with this was a cumbersome because you
这很麻烦，因为你
needed to provide a callback as as an
需要提供回调作为
implementation of an interface and there
接口的实现
was no way to simply chain other
无法简单地将其他人联系在一起
execution on top of other executions on
在其他执行之上
top of it so if you just execute it
它的顶部，所以如果您只执行它
another synchronous call within the
内的另一个同步呼叫
callback you
回调你
- spaghetti code which is referenced as
-意大利面条代码，称为
callback hell because there you have too
回调地狱，因为那里
many brackets next it inside complex
复杂里面的许多括号
nested inside so with a Java 8 there is
嵌套在其中，因此使用Java 8
a new thing or it's not already it's not
新事物或它不是已经不是
new but Java 8 what the completable
新但Java 8可完成的功能
future has new thing which allowed to
未来有新事物允许
chain these invocations and to create
链接这些调用并创建
readable code while it was still a
可读代码，虽然它仍然是
synchronous and with new tracks are so
同步和新的轨道是如此
reactive API it's now possible to chain
反应性API，现在可以链接
the callbacks with completable future
具有可完成的未来的回调
but don't know not only with computable
但不仅知道可计算的
future but you can plug in your
未来，但您可以插入
alternative mechanism for example rxjava
替代机制，例如rxjava
handler which are is Java is quite
Java的处理程序是相当
popular when writing a reactive code and
编写反应式代码时很流行，并且
John Jarvis natively supports it so you
John Jarvis原生支持它，因此您
want the only thing you need to have is
想要你唯一需要的就是
a factory that can turn the result of
一个可以将结果转化为
the service call into an hour exert our
一个小时的服务电话将我们的
observer and then we can use it within
观察者，然后我们可以在
the same fluent API of jax-rs no need
不需要jax-rs的相同API
don't need to wrap it into a different
不需要将其包装到另一个
object you can just change the method
对象，您可以更改方法
calls and just change change the return
打电话，只是改变改变回报
value to what you wouldn't need to work
重视您不需要工作的东西
with the library so that's my nice but
与图书馆，所以这是我很好，但
it by default the reactive call would
默认情况下，反应式调用
return a compostable future or motor
返回可堆肥的未来或动力
more precisely completion stage but you
更确切地说是完成阶段，但是你
can override it and have a plug in your
可以覆盖它并插入您的
factory to return a different different
工厂退换不同
time so you can easily change more
时间，以便您可以轻松地进行更多更改
computations and turn it into the stream
计算并将其转化为流
of invocations it's it's not technically
的调用不是技术上的
a stream of data because simple reactive
数据流，因为简单的反应式
simple rest call would just wait for the
简单的休息电话只会等待
rest coat of thing to be finished then
然后把待办事项
it can turn it in
它可以把它
or process it into a java object by
或将其处理为Java对象
parsing JSON or XML and then you still
解析JSON或XML，然后您仍然
have the final object in the end but it
最后有最后一个对象，但是它
makes it easier to write synchronous
使同步编写更容易
code so that your original blah thread
代码，以便您的原始blah线程
is not blocked if you want to use reals
如果要使用实数，则不会被阻止
streams with jax-rs you would go with
jax-rs将与您一起流
the SSE the server sent events which
SSE服务器发送事件
allow to initiate a call and then in the
允许发起呼叫，然后在
server can send individual events stream
服务器可以发送单个事件流
of data as a server sent events which
数据作为服务器发送的事件
you can again chain with a complete loop
您可以再次用一个完整的循环链
of future callbacks so that's the new
未来的回调，所以这是新的
addition of reactive client so CI back
添加反应式客户端，以便CI返回
to the application that we were talking
到我们正在谈论的应用程序
about so the server sent events is
关于，因此服务器发送的事件是
really the thing that I wanted to to
我真的很想
talk about here so I was playing about
在这里谈论，所以我在玩
with certain events for it for this
为此有一些事件
quite a few months ago now actually but
其实几个月前
basically the jax-rs specification
基本上是jax-rs规范
wasn't finalized at that point so all I
当时还没有完成，所以我
was doing was really just using the the
当时所做的实际上只是使用
Jersey implementation of it which was
它的泽西岛实施
kind of where the jax-rs Edition had
jax-rs Edition的版本
come from so we can see here we got this
来自，所以我们可以看到这里
SSE endpoint here or this is the Jersey
SSE端点在这里，或者这是泽西岛
API is not jax-rs but I wanted to have
API不是jax-rs，但我想拥有
it here just so that you can compare
它只是为了让您可以比较
what it was like to what it is like now
到现在是什么样
so here you can see that we are
所以在这里你可以看到我们
returning type of event output annotated
返回的事件输出类型已注释
with producer of sse featured observers
与sse制作人一起的特色观察员
and events obviously now we've got a
和事件显然现在我们有一个
proper media type you know that we can
适当的媒体类型，您知道我们可以
produce so we needed to create a new
生产，所以我们需要创建一个新的
thread and do everything in that
线程并做那一切
separate thread nothing in there is
单独的线程里没有东西
particularly
尤其
complicated but it's a lot of extra co2
复杂但有很多额外的二氧化碳
right and just a lot of extra chance for
对，还有很多额外的机会
bugs so just to compare that with the
的错误，所以只是将其与
jax-rs code really it doesn't even need
jax-rs代码确实不需要
to be as complex as they even it can be
变得尽可能复杂
as simple as just SSE broadcast
就像SSE广播一样简单
broadcast that you can see down the
广播，您可以看到
bottom there so the reason that we've
在那里，所以我们的原因
got two methods is that there is a get
有两种方法是
to end point which can receive a client
到可以接待客户的终点
request as an SSE event sync now this
作为SSE事件的请求现在同步
event sync is just something that you
事件同步只是您的事情
can register in your broadcaster so that
可以在您的广播公司中注册，以便
then the second method is where we
然后第二种方法是
actually broadcast events so because
实际广播事件是因为
we've actually also annotated the second
我们实际上还注释了第二个
method there with a post it means that
那里有贴子的方法，这意味着
you can not only you know call this
你不仅可以知道这个
broadcast method from within the same
同一内部的广播方法
class within the same application you
在同一个应用程序中
can have like a separate micro service
可以像单独的微服务一样
that sends something to be then
发送一些东西然后
broadcast by a separate micro service to
由单独的微服务广播到
all of its consumers so you can see at
所有的消费者，因此您可以在
the top there the first one I've got is
最上面的我第一个是
the event output one there's actually
事件输出实际上是一个
two lines there the first isn't
两行，第一行不是
necessary but it's an example of how you
必要的，但这是您如何做的一个例子
can just send a single event so you can
可以只发送一个事件，因此您可以
use that kind of API there but the the
在那里使用那种API，但是
SSE broadcaster I think is the really
我认为SSE广播公司是真正的
useful one for the purposes that we want
对于我们想要的目的有用的
now the next thing to think about is
现在接下来要考虑的是
from an architectural standpoint is
从架构的角度来看是
where where do you plug this into the
您在哪里将其插入
application see at the moment I've
我现在看到的应用程序
already got CDI events close to CDI
已经有接近CDI的CDI事件
events between the stock ticker and a
股票行情自动收录器与
stock web services and then I've got
股票网络服务，然后我得到了
WebSockets in the front-end so we could
WebSockets在前端，因此我们可以
do is replace the WebSockets on the
要做的是替换上的WebSockets
front end so we've still got a CDO event
前端，所以我们还有CDO活动
bus between the stock ticker and the
股票报价器和
stock web and then it's just the
股票网站，然后
JavaScript SSE client that we have to
我们必须使用的JavaScript SSE客户端
that we have to create basically own
我们必须创建基本上自己的
that the changes between those and
那些之间的变化和
fortunately haven't got those on slides
幸运的是还没有幻灯片
but they are minimal
但它们很小
it's not much to do that but when we
这样做不多，但是当我们
spoke a little bit earlier about the the
早一点谈到了
way that we manage these things the
我们管理这些东西的方式
other option that we've got is the
我们拥有的另一个选择是
jax-rs SSE client and really that the
jax-rs SSE客户端，实际上
decision here is where you want to
决定在这里是你想去的地方
orchestrate our micro services if we've
如果我们已经安排了微服务
got a more complex scenario with this
有了一个更复杂的场景
where you've got a particular functional
您具有特定功能的地方
process that you want to run with
您要运行的过程
several different work so you think five
几项不同的工作，所以您认为五
or six would you want to orchestrate
或六个你要编排
that within a JavaScript browser-based
在基于JavaScript浏览器的
application or would you want to
应用程序还是您想
orchestrate it on the backend and then
在后端进行编排，然后
have your JavaScript web page be more of
让您的JavaScript网页更具吸引力
a thin client to it I would generally
我通常会是一个瘦客户
prefer to do it the second way have
宁愿做第二种方式
everything be kind of orchestrated at
一切都精心策划
the backend and then have a thin client
后端，然后有一个瘦客户端
at the front but I know that's not
在前面，但我知道那不是
everyone's preference and either way as
每个人的偏好，无论哪种方式
possible so again I have a look at the
可能的话，我再次看看
SSE client code so from within jax-rs
SSE客户端代码来自jax-rs
now this is the old jersey method again
现在这又是旧球衣的方法
we can create a new client builder this
我们可以创建一个新的客户端构建器
actually quite similar to the new jax-rs
实际上非常类似于新的jax-rs
api but we're just using different
api，但我们只是使用不同的
objects and things here here we need to
这里的物体和东西，我们需要
actually return the event source and
实际返回事件源并
we're doing create a new client builder
我们正在创建一个新的客户端生成器
registering that and targeting things to
注册并将其定位到
a stocktake a URL so we need to know
盘点URL，所以我们需要知道
this URL in advance which is tricky
预先输入这个网址很棘手
we've got a way around that I'll talk
我们有办法解决，我会说
about later the event listener we need
关于稍后我们需要的事件监听器
to add and then register to the events
添加并注册到事件
source so we just create a new lesson
源，所以我们只是创建一个新课程
that obviously this was slightly old
显然这有点旧
code so actually that could be replaced
因此实际上可以被替换的代码
with a lambda rather than an anonymous
用lambda而不是匿名
method this is in jax-rs 2.1 so we've
方法是在jax-rs 2.1中，所以我们已经
set that into basically the three
将其基本上设置为三个
different methods that we got
我们得到的不同方法
an EJB that I'm doing a post construct
我正在执行后期构造的EJB
in a pre destroy on the post construct
在后结构的预破坏中
initialized everything's very
初始化一切都非常
initialized the client in the web target
在Web目标中初始化客户端
exactly the same as before and we're
和以前完全一样，我们
setting the source as an SSE event
将源设置为SSE事件
source rather than just a normal event
来源，而不仅仅是正常事件
source and then just calling the observe
源，然后只调用观察
method so in the observe method this is
方法，所以在观察方法中，这是
how we actually consume the event so
我们实际上如何消费事件
we've just got a nice brief lambda there
我们在那里有了一个简短的lambda
just to handle all the events that come
只是为了处理所有即将发生的事件
in again I'm using Jason B API to
我再次使用Jason B API
deserialize
反序列化
stock events that come in and providing
提供的库存事件
the throwable print stack trace
可抛出的打印堆栈跟踪
method reference there for anything that
那里的方法参考
goes wrong so we don't need to handle
出错了，所以我们不需要处理
that in any more detail and finally I
再详细一点，最后我
just do source not open and then these
只是不要打开源，然后这些
events will start to be consumed at the
事件将开始在
end there I've got a destroy method to
到此为止，我有一种销毁方法
gracefully close that I saw so we don't
优雅地关闭我所看到的，这样我们就不会
get any errors on the remote side and it
在远端得到任何错误，它
just finds the client consumer just
只是找到客户消费者
disappears
消失了
this was the if you wanted to sell
如果你想卖的话
JavaScript to do things so in my
JavaScript在我的机器上做
particular example because I'm running
特别的例子，因为我正在跑步
this on a or I would have been running
这在一个或我会一直在运行
it on a laptop with everything was
它在笔记本电脑上的一切都被
localhost you can see that obviously
本地主机，您可以清楚地看到
you've got cross origin issues if you've
如果您有跨源问题
requesting from two different ports so
从两个不同的端口请求
I've got a little diagram there that I
我那里有一个小图
got from developer mozilla.org and I
来自开发人员mozilla.org和我
won't go into that this is just a
不会说这只是一个
standard response filter for jax-rs just
仅用于jax-rs的标准响应过滤器
adding that a single header just to say
添加一个标题只是为了说
yep it's okay the cross origin request
是的，可以跨源请求
don't matter for real this wouldn't
没关系，这不会
really be a problem because they would
真的是一个问题，因为他们会
always be from the same domain so we'd
总是来自同一个域，所以我们会
know that that was okay so really ahead
知道那没关系，所以真的很前方
of schedule now but yeah so the next
现在的时间表，但是是的，下一个
thing that one is to look at so we've
要看的一件事，所以我们已经
added a few jar v8 api's to kind of make
添加了一些jar v8 api来制作
things a little bit more generic what a
事情有点通用
next one is look at was the future of a
下一个是看未来
Java EE and where it might go
Java EE及其发展方向
or II for J or whatever it gets called
或II代表J或任何被称为
and it furtively because I think a lot
偷偷地因为我想了很多
of the people that are involved in the
参与其中的人
micro profile efforts have got grand
微型配置文件的努力取得了巨大成功
visions that actually micro profile
实际上是微观的异象
itself is gaining a lot of traction a
本身正在获得很大的吸引力
lot more than I think than many people
比我想的要多得多
expected I think there is a strong
预计我认为有一个强大的
feeling that the future of Java EE if
感觉Java EE的未来是否
you want to see it now look to micro
你想现在看到它看起来微
profile personally this is again like
个人简介这再次像
completely my personal view I think
我认为完全是我的个人观点
actually this is really is the future of
其实这真的是未来
Java EE whether my profile gets subsumed
Java EE是否包含我的个人资料
into it or not I don't know I hope it
不知道我不希望
doesn't I think I quite like it as a
我不觉得我很喜欢
separate project where we can innovate
我们可以创新的独立项目
and it has that extra freedom to just do
它有额外的自由去做
things that people need I know that IBM
人们需要的东西我知道IBM
and Red Hat are investing heavily into
和红帽正在大力投资
it they've got quite a few people
他们有很多人
working on it we empower our as well as
致力于它，我们赋予我们以及
our Tommy tribe but then also we've got
我们的汤米部落，但我们还有
tons of people in the community so we've
社区里有很多人，所以我们
got lots of community Apache committers
有很多社区Apache提交者
that are putting a lot of time and
花费很多时间，
effort into micro profile and that the
努力进入微观形象，
whole goal of is to be really really
的全部目标是要真的真的
community community oriented so anyone
以社区为导向，所以任何人
who wants to get involved with it can it
想要参与其中的人可以
can get involved with it there are
可以参与其中
stands actually in the exhibition hall
实际上站在展厅里
downstairs so you can go and find out a
楼下，这样你就可以找到一个
bit more about it and how to get
关于它的更多信息以及如何获得
involved Oh
参与哦
put some transitions on there yeah so
在那边放一些过渡是的
here is the dependency for the 1.1
这是1.1的依赖
version which is the current release
当前发行版
like I said 1.2 is imminent it's
就像我说的1.2迫在眉睫
basically code complete at the moment
目前基本上代码已完成
you need to you know specify the type is
您需要知道指定的类型是
parm and specify that's provided because
解析并指定所提供的内容，因为
it is just an API there's no actual jar
这只是一个API，没有实际的jar
implementation yet the implementations
实施但实施
are provided in the same way that Java
以与Java相同的方式提供
implementations are by vendors so those
由供应商实施，因此
are all the things that you need to do
是您需要做的所有事情
to set how a stock ticker URL that we
设置我们的股票行情URL
had on our sse client class so now the
在我们的sse客户类上，所以现在
issue that we had there was that
我们在那里的问题是
we had our jax-rs clients that needed to
我们的jax-rs客户需要
connect to a URL that it didn't know
连接到它不知道的URL
already because you don't know where
已经因为你不知道在哪里
it's going to be until it starts up if
直到它启动，如果
you're in say communities where the
您所在的社区
remote server might not be there yet we
远程服务器可能还不存在
don't know we don't know ahead of time
不知道我们不知道提前
where the endpoint is going to be it
终点将在哪里
might change and we need to react to
可能会改变，我们需要对
that so the config API gives us the
因此，配置API为我们提供了
ability to look for a property that we
寻找我们所拥有的财产的能力
set in as far as the API is concerned
就API而言设置
three places
三个地方
that's system properties environment
那是系统属性环境
variables and a file in the is it the
变量和文件中的是
the meta-inf or web-inf for the config
配置的meta-inf或web-inf
property so it's my perfect mess yes I'm
财产，所以这是我的完美烂摊子，是的
in the meta-inf by an F directory of
在meta-inf中的F目录
your application you can create a micro
您的应用程序可以创建一个微型
profile that properties file which has
配置文件具有
all these properties in and that's a
所有这些属性，那就是
valid config source as well each of them
有效的配置源以及每个
has got different ordinal priorities so
有不同的顺序优先顺序，因此
that you can always know which one is
你总能知道哪一个是
going to be preferred so we're injecting
将成为首选，所以我们正在注入
that that how to set a default value as
那如何将默认值设置为
well so that we can you know handle if
好，这样我们就可以知道
it's not there and that's all you need
它不在那里，这就是您所需要的
to do to use it there at the top I've
去在顶部使用它
given an example of how to actually run
给出了如何实际运行的示例
everything that we were doing there so
我们在那里所做的一切
the stock web application here it's a
股票网络应用程序，这是一个
micro bundle we really kind of in the
微束我们真的在
project we're kind of building a new
项目，我们正在建立一个新的
bridge our with PI our micro but I'm
用PI桥接我们的微信，但我
setting the micro deployed at stock
设置微型部署库存
ticker dot URL property as a system
代码点URL属性作为系统
property and that will be then picked up
财产，然后将其拿起
by the application which works
通过有效的应用程序
beautifully if I had a demo but there's
如果我有一个演示很漂亮，但是有
also another option that we've added for
我们为之添加的另一个选项
pi our server
pi我们的服务器
obviously there's we that are familiar
显然我们很熟悉
with GlassFish if you haven't used pyro
如果您没有使用pyro，请与GlassFish一起使用
server yet and you should definitely
服务器呢，你绝对应该
check it out but we've added a few extra
检查一下，但我们添加了一些额外的功能
AAS admin commands to set and get
AAS管理员命令来设置和获取
conflict properties the reason why I
冲突属性我之所以如此
wanted to demonstrate this one here is
想在这里展示这个
that we've got
我们有
property name property value are quite
属性名称属性值相当
clear but then I've added the source of
清楚，但后来我添加了
cluster so I said that there are three
集群，所以我说有三个
default sources for the micro profile
微型配置文件的默认来源
config API those you can rely on for any
您可以依赖的配置API
micro profile implementation whether
微型配置文件的实施是否
it's waffle ice warm liberty or Tommy or
华夫饼干冰温暖的自由或汤米或
payara
帕亚拉
that they're reliable here though we've
他们在这里很可靠，尽管我们已经
got a source of cluster so that means
有集群的来源，这意味着
that all those properties then can be
那么所有这些属性可以是
stored in hazel cast and then
储存在淡褐色铸模中，然后
distributed to any other cluster member
分发给任何其他集群成员
that joins that cluster at any later
以后再加入该集群
point in time so once that's been set
时间点，因此一旦设置
any other member that joins will get an
加入的任何其他成员将获得一个
store that cluster so that if your
存储该群集，以便如果您
initial member goes down the property is
最初的成员​​是财产
still set and is still available for
仍然设置并且仍可用于
your application which again when we're
您的应用程序再次
looking at things that are using things
看着正在使用的东西
like our at clustered annotations who
就像我们在集群注释中
got close to singleton that will still
接近单身，仍然会
be available to that singleton when it
当那个单身人士可用时
starts up later on so that's quite a
稍后开始，所以相当
neat little convenience method there so
干净利落的便利方法
really really ahead of time I hope
我真的真的希望提前
you've got like 50 minutes of questions
你有50分钟的问题
maybe I'll prepare to talk without a
也许我会准备不说话
demo next time so yeah I'd wanted to
下次演示，是的，我想
recap a little bit about what we talked
回顾一下我们所说的话
about I'm mostly highlight the fact that
我主要是强调
a huge amount of what I've talked about
我所说的很多
aside from the API is has actually come
除了API实际上是
between four years previous when Java 7
在Java 7之前的四年之间
was announced to this year when joffrey
是乔佛里宣布到今年
8 was announced all of this has not come
宣布8一切还没有到来
from the Java EE specs themselves it's
从Java EE规范本身来看
come from the vendors seeing what's
从供应商那里看到什么
happening in the world around them and
发生在他们周围的世界中
reacting to this kind of change so Java
对这种变化做出反应，所以Java
EE is incredibly adaptable and the the
EE适应性极强，
vendors themselves that have created
已创建的供应商本身
these new distributions I even spring
这些新发行版我什至春天
which obviously isn't Java EE but does
显然不是Java EE，但是
use y2 Java API s and even their
使用y2 Java API甚至是
influence is helping to kind of drive
影响力有助于推动
things forward and even though that
事情向前发展，即使那
there was definitely a significant delay
肯定有很大的延迟
in the release of Java 8
在Java 8版本中
the industry didn't stop moving and
这个行业并没有停止发展，
there's been a lot of change that's been
发生了很多变化
driven by illness implementations and
由疾病实施和
finally just that Eclipse micro profile
最后就是Eclipse的微概要文件
is I think where there's a lot of
我认为那里有很多
innovation happening at the moment
目前正在发生的创新
there are lots of interesting specs if
如果有很多有趣的规格
you are really interested in looking at
你真的很感兴趣
my micro service deployment it's really
我的微服务部署真的
good to look at if you go down to the
很高兴看看，如果你下去
Exhibition Centre at any point I think
我认为展览中心在任何时候
during the conference there will be
会议期间，
demos of Micra profile happening there
那里发生的Micra个人资料演示
so it'd be really good to go and check
所以去检查真的很好
out and hopefully I think some of those
希望我认为其中一些
demos should include some 1.2 specs but
演示应包括一些1.2规格，但
because they so new there's not many
因为它们很新，所以没有很多
implementations around just yet and I
我周围的实现
think that's everything that I had was
认为这就是我所拥有的一切
everything I had without my laptop CI
没有笔记本电脑CI的一切
sorry that things didn't quite work out
抱歉，事情还没有解决
as planned
正如计划
yeah are there any questions we've got a
是的，我们有什么疑问吗
lot of time for them yes great
对他们来说是很多时间，太好了
yes yes yes
对对对
well I know that sorry okay yes so I'll
好吧，我知道抱歉，是的，所以我会
repeat the question so that the question
重复问题，以便问题
was that the clustered CDI event bus
是集群的CDI事件总线
obviously is very pyro specific and the
显然是非常热解的
question was do you know if there are
问题是你是否知道
any plans to get that to be like a
任何计划使它像一个
proper standardized feature I know the
我知道适当的标准化功能
CDI to brings asynchronous events on
CDI带来异步事件
table know a bit more than me about that
桌子比我了解的更多
but it's not same thing there my my good
但是我的天哪不是同一件事
feeling is that it would be very
感觉就是
difficult to standardize on and the
难以标准化，
reason for that is that even the the J
原因是，即使J
cache specification which is provided by
提供的缓存规范
hazel caste is that does not actually
淡褐色种姓实际上不是
include any clustering and I think there
包括任何群集，我认为在那里
is that there is not a lot of appetite
胃口不大
from people writing specs to include any
从编写规范的人包括
sort of clustering technology as part of
集群技术的一部分
the implementation so yeah it would be
实施，所以是的
amazing if it could be I think it would
如果可能的话，我会感到惊讶
be such a useful thing to have but I I
是一件有用的事情，但是
would be surprised if it does yes
如果是的话会感到惊讶
absolutely yes and it's something that's
绝对是的，那是
in in player obviously we're looking for
在球员显然我们正在寻找
with PI or a5 the intention is to kind
与PI或a5的意图是
of remove the old domain model and go to
删除旧的域模型并转到
more towards a domain data fabric so
更倾向于域数据结构
yeah it is going to be much more like
是的，它将更像
that I know vertex I think are quite
我知道我认为顶点非常
similar in that they use hazel cast as
相似之处在于他们使用淡褐色
well I don't know if they've got any
好吧，我不知道他们有没有
similar kind of technology to the
类似的技术
clustered CDI events but what ups they
群集的CDI事件，但它们又起什么作用
don't figure would any sort of events
不知道会发生什么事情
think that they obviously have messaging
认为他们显然有消息
the but their time of messaging
但是他们的通讯时间
messaging mechanism is based on the
消息传递机制基于
sending JSON data so that it can be
发送JSON数据，以便可以
distributed to any kind of language
分发到任何一种语言
because vertex supports not only Java
因为顶点不仅支持Java
but Java Script groovy and other
但是Java Script Groovy和其他
languages but they also rely on the
语言，但他们也依靠
handle cast equality and
处理演员平等
like distributed data grades are very
像分布式数据等级
interesting because there are quite easy
有趣，因为很容易
to setup
建立
they're very complex so you wouldn't
它们非常复杂，所以您不会
want to write them in your application
想要在您的应用程序中编写它们
you'd rather use a existing proven
您宁愿使用现有的经过验证的
solution they provide lots of
他们提供了很多解决方案
interesting features and they are very
有趣的功能，它们非常
easy to use and the to show that and the
易于使用和显示，以及
city has been even buzzing by our
城市甚至被我们嗡嗡作响
microphone by our server a demonstration
我们服务器上的麦克风演示
of how easy it's it's to integrate a
集成一个多么容易
zorka's to build a solution to
zorka的解决方案
distribute messages we are CDI and in
分发我们是CDI的消息
fact the API which is in power is only
实际上，有效的API仅
two annotations so you can and these two
两个注释，所以您可以和这两个
annotations are basically qualifiers in
注释基本上是
CDI
CDI
so even if the implementation is not
所以即使实现不是
there an Iranian application an
那里有伊朗人的申请
application that uses CDI even boss you
使用CDI的应用程序甚至可以让您老大
run it on a different application server
在其他应用程序服务器上运行
you can still plug in your serial
您仍然可以插入序列号
extension or just a CDI observer and
扩展或只是CDI观察员，以及
plug in your own solution it can be
插入您自己的解决方案
based on hazel caste when you have to
根据榛树种姓，
create and create it by our server and
由我们的服务器创建和创建
micro have have it built-in but even
微型有内置的，但是
just use the PI API in these two
只需在这两个中使用PI API
qualifiers you just put the dependency
限定词，您只需放置依赖项
on on these two qualifiers and then you
在这两个预选赛上，然后
can plug in your own observer and
可以插入自己的观察者
distribute the messages yourself if just
如果只是分发您自己的消息
PI R makes it easy because it provides
PI R使它变得容易，因为它提供了
this list for you but it demonstrates
这个清单给你，但它展示了
how easy it is to plug additional things
插入其他东西有多容易
with the help of CDI the CDI API is very
借助CDI，CDI API非常
very easy to use very straightforward
非常容易使用，非常简单
and very easy to plug in two additional
而且很容易插入另外两个
extensions
扩展名
yes I guess it were there anyone else
是的，我猜那里还有其他人
that had questions or we've got a couple
有问题或者我们有几个
more that we can carry with I guess yes
我们可以随身携带的更多东西
yeah
是的
[Music]
[音乐]
yes so I thought that myself
是的，所以我以为自己
I don't know particularly why that's not
我特别不知道为什么不是这样
half of their then if you are too
如果你也是他们的一半
familiar with it personally I'd like if
我想亲自熟悉一下
that was the case I'd like to just be
我就是这样想的
able to see you lie straight to yanil
能够看到你直接向亚尼尔撒谎
because I'd be really nice yes
因为我会很好
yeah yeah I mean actually on that point
是的，我是说实际上
Andre pointed out the other day which I
安德烈指出我有一天
didn't include in the presentation that
在演示文稿中没有包括
obviously service and events has got its
显然服务和事件已经得到
own convenience methods for serializing
自己方便的序列化方法
to Jason formats as well so that there's
也可以转换成Jason格式
a lot of this kind of almost like I just
很多这样的几乎就像我一样
repeated things in my opinion is that
我认为重复的事情是
maybe Jason as a format is a bit
也许杰森的格式有点
different from eczema and jugs B was
与湿疹和水罐B不同的是
specifically designed for axonal and it
专为轴突而设计
lacked some some support for edge cases
缺乏一些对极端情况的支持
in in Jason that's why I created they
在Jason中，这就是我创建它们的原因
created Jason be to support it as a
创建杰森是为了支持它
first-class citizen to support azem and
头等公民支持阿泽姆和
some some application servers I'm not
一些我不是的应用服务器
sure about bias but some plication
肯定有偏见，但有些折衷
servers support in Jack's B annotations
杰克的B批注中的服务器支持
to convert an object into JSON and back
将对象转换为JSON然后返回
but this was kind of limited to if you
但这仅限于您
hit DC each case use cases it was hard
每个案例用例都很难达到DC
to get it get the result and you expect
得到它的结果，你期望
it would work but if you really want it
它会工作，但如果您真的想要
to conform to specific format in the
以符合特定格式
JSON serialize data it was hard to get
JSON序列化数据很难
the names of the fields right it would
正确的字段名称
just create a random random fields but
只是创建一个随机的随机字段，但
there is obviously no schema for JSON
显然没有JSON的架构
but if there was it will be hard to fit
但是如果有的话就很难适应
the schema and make it valid against
模式并使其针对
this the schema
这个架构
so Jax B is possible to use and it was
因此可以使用Jax B，
used
用过的
it wasn't standard Standa was normally
这不是标准的Standa通常
it was standardized against a against
它被标准化为反对
XML but some application servers also
XML，但也有一些应用服务器
could use Jack's B annotations to
可以使用杰克的B注释来
produce Jason and also opposed to Jason
生产杰森，也反对杰森
but it was lacking some features and
但它缺少一些功能，
since juggs B is already a part of Java
因为juggs B已经是Java的一部分
language not only Java EE was much
语言不仅是Java EE
harder to to extend Jack's B and add
很难扩展Jack's B并添加
some more features into it them to
他们有一些更多的功能
create a new specification which is
创建一个新的规范是
specifically tailored for Jason yeah I
专为杰森（Jason）量身定制
guess another point on that was we just
猜想另一点是我们只是
that I think when Jason B was proposed
我认为当杰森B被提议时
it was very deliberately limited just to
它被故意限制为
avoid you know becoming this how huge
避免你知道变得如此巨大
sprawling thing that tried to you know
试图让你知道的东西
be everything to everyone I think I know
成为我想知道的所有人的一切
I know there was a decision made her to
我知道她有一个决定
kind of limit it to let's just you know
限制它让你知道
do one thing and do it well
一件事做好
yeah so I ideally I would like to see
是的，所以理想情况下，我希望看到
something that's just you know that the
只是你知道的东西
same annotation and the same thing where
相同的注释和相同的内容
you can you know just or plug in
你可以只知道或插入
whatever data format that you want but
您想要的任何数据格式，但是
I'm not enough for a developer to know
我还不足以让开发人员知道
how feasible that is so maybe it's just
这是多么可行，所以也许
I have a particularly complex problem to
我有一个特别复杂的问题
solve you know and Andres given a few
解决你知道的，安德烈斯给了一些
examples of how it is quite complex
复杂的例子
yes
是
yes that the micro profile config yes
是的，微型配置文件配置是
yes yep it is very possible so this was
是的，这很有可能，所以这是
something that I nearly did with with
我几乎用的东西
with the demo but I thought that if I
与演示，但我认为，如果我
did do it then maybe I'd run out of time
做到了，那我可能没时间了
ironically so yeah we're basically
具有讽刺意味的是，是的，我们基本上
discussing this in the office but so
在办公室里讨论这个，但是
that the use case that I've got here is
我在这里得到的用例是
that we we don't know this URL fizz
我们不知道这个URL的嘶嘶声
micro-service ahead of time so we need
提前提供微服务，因此我们需要
to kind of run time to discover it
有种运行时间来发现它
but then the remote micro service that
但随后的远程微服务
may also not know it's the thing ahead
可能还不知道这是未来的事情
of time so really what we need to do is
时间，所以实际上我们需要做的是
have the remote one to kind of set a
有一个远程设置
property in some config source now that
现在在某些配置源中的属性
there's a company called I think config
有一家公司我认为配置
hub which do like a server which can you
集线器，就像服务器，您可以
know you can set and get properties from
知道您可以从中设置和获取属性
so that the config API was deliberately
因此，配置API是故意的
I'll let Andre talk a bit in a minute he
我待会儿让安德烈谈一谈
helped to specify it or there was a very
帮助指定它，或者有一个非常
deliberate decision made to avoid doing
避免做出故意决定
that so we were they wanted it to be
所以我们是他们希望它成为
read-only specifically to avoid things
专门为避免事情而只读
being set so the it is possible to do
被设置，所以有可能做
this so you kind of to set a conflict
这让您有点矛盾
property dynamically through code what
通过代码动态属性
you'd need to do is create your own
您需要做的就是创建自己的
config source right and then set that in
配置源权限，然后在
that way using the SPI that's available
这样使用可用的SPI
so the reason why I didn't want to do
所以我不想做的原因
that is because it's moving outside of
那是因为它移出了
the scope of configuration of an
配置范围
application and into being a service
应用并成为服务
registry effectively so you know like at
有效地注册，所以您知道在
CD or some other ones that I've just
CD或其他我刚发行的CD
forgotten any others console maybe and
可能忘记了其他任何控制台
it seemed too far outside the bounds of
似乎超出了
what config really was so I don't if you
真正的配置是什么，所以如果您不
your honor correct wife
你的荣誉正确的妻子
not sure if I correct with maybe add
不知道我是否可以添加
well you didn't say and simply the
好吧，你没有说，只是
configuration API which is part of micro
配置API，它是micro的一部分
profile have has two different
个人资料有两个不同
components one is for reading the
组件之一是用于阅读
configuration and this this provides two
配置，这提供了两个
different api's just for playing Java
不同的API仅用于播放Java
API with static static methods and with
具有静态和静态方法的API
serialization so that you can inject
序列化，以便您可以注入
values but it also has an extension or
值，但也有扩展名或
SPI in interfaces oh and you can provide
接口中的SPI，您可以提供
your own configuration sources within
您自己的配置源
your applications so you're just
您的应用程序，因此您只是
implementing interface when she has I
有我的时候实现接口
think four methods one of them is get
认为其中一种方法是得到
get value which gets the name of the key
获取值，获取键的名称
and you provide the value from from this
然后您从中提供价值
object and the configuration mechanism
对象和配置机制
detects there's your implementation of
检测到您的实现
config source via second service locator
通过第二个服务定位器配置源
so we need to create an additional
所以我们需要创建一个额外的
service file today to find to register
今天要查找的服务文件进行注册
this implementation and configuration
此实现和配置
are specific oh it's not a specification
是具体的哦，这不是规范
in terms of jsr but the configuration
就jsr而言，但配置
mechanism specifies ordering of these
机制指定这些的顺序
sources so there are defaults or config
来源，因此有默认值或配置
sources for reading prover for providing
阅读证明者提供的资料
values from property system properties
来自属性系统属性的值
from environment variables and I have
从环境变量，我有
some value of order or some some index
一些定单值或一些指数
to order these config sources yes yes
订购这些配置源是是
you can you can change them you can
你可以改变他们你可以
change them then basically the the
改变他们，然后基本上
source is whether higher order are asked
来源是是否要求更高的顺序
first and if the value is not there the
首先，如果该值不存在
other sources are asked until it's found
询问其他来源，直到找到
so you can provide a config source with
因此您可以提供一个配置源
higher high order high priority and you
高高阶高优先级，您
can overwrite any value there and it's
可以覆盖那里的任何值，它是
still within the application you just
仍然在应用程序中
register it with with the service
向服务注册
locator mechanism with the service file
服务文件的定位器机制
and
和
what the configuration does it will
它会做什么配置
detect the config source it will ask it
检测配置源将询问它
for for the value and it will provided
为价值，它将提供
them when it's required by the
他们在需要时
application yes
申请是
okay it's a really really brand new
好吧，这是一个全新的体验
feature that it's actually the the demo
它实际上是演示的功能
that I was gonna run what was it what
我要去跑什么
was the question that I'm sorry I should
是一个问题，我很抱歉我应该
it was the question to get right about
这是正确的问题
which server which node in the cluster
哪个服务器在集群中的哪个节点
is the master is that correct the thing
是主人是正确的东西
is that the advantage of hezekiah that's
希西家的优势是
why I said it's very complex and you
为什么我说这很复杂，你呢
wouldn't want to write it it's a
不想写它是一个
distributed memory or distributed data
分布式内存或分布式数据
cluster so it doesn't have a notion of a
集群，所以它没有一个概念
master you just connected to it from
您刚刚从其连接的主人
from a node or even from a client which
从一个节点甚至从一个客户端
is not part of the cluster and you can
不属于集群，您可以
send the data there and it's evenly
将数据发送到那里，并且均匀地
distributed across the cluster is about
分布在整个集群中的是
support data distribution and
支持数据分发和
replication so I think but if all it
复制，所以我认为但如果全部
copies the data three times so that it's
将数据复制三遍，以便
always at least at on three notes and
总是至少在三个音符上
when any node goes down it's a very
当任何一个节点出现故障时，
distributed so that it's again on three
分布，以便再次在三个
different nodes so it's always there and
不同的节点，所以它总是在那里
there is no single point of failure with
没有单点故障
has a cost you can you can bring down
有一个可以降低的成本
any any notes if there is at least one
任何至少有一个音符
node the data is there if you have
如果您有节点，则数据在那里
enough memory on the node to store the
节点上有足够的内存来存储
data so it's just enough to to send the
数据，因此足以发送
data from a node and is distributed and
来自节点的数据并被分发
then there's no no master it's always
那就没有主人了
available if the data is not available
如果数据不可用，则可用
the note
笔记
hello cards will ask other nodes to
你好卡会问其他节点
bring will and bring the data from them
带来意愿并从他们那里带来数据
yeah it is a friendly feature so it's
是的，这是一个友好的功能，因此
it's not even released yet I think we
它甚至还没有发布，我想我们
depending on how testing goes this is a
根据测试的方式，这是一个
cluster that clustered yes yeah so the
是的，是的，所以
the obviously the way that I got it in
显然我得到它的方式
my demo you kind of start at multiple of
我的演示，您从多个
these stockticker
这些股票行情
yoruba jars they've all got the
约鲁巴罐子，他们都有
application and if there's already one
应用程序，如果已经有一个
running that's running this singleton
运行正在运行此单例
then it just doesn't start
那就没有开始
the Hib timer and then obviously
Hib计时器，然后显然
wasteful want to go down and I guess you
浪费下来，我想你
know however the partitions are set up
知道分区已设置
so now it comes designates one notice I
所以现在它来指定一个通知我
took the primary copy of the data and
取得了数据的主要副本，
then like backups around it I don't know
然后像周围的备份我不知道
how it would decide which backup to
如何决定要备份哪个
reinitialize but then that's how it
重新初始化，但是就是这样
would work so you had at the moment it's
会工作，所以您现在就拥有
I think it's just ejbs that it works on
我认为它只是在ejbs上起作用
but yeah we I say we the engineer that's
但是，是的，我说我们是
doing it is it's working on the CDI
这样做是在CDI上工作
beans as well initially I was answering
一开始我也在回答豆子
a different question I thought I thought
我以为是一个不同的问题
you were asking about the configurations
您在询问配置
conflict source which is also based on
冲突源也基于
heads of cars with the cluster config
带有群集配置的汽车头部
source we have in Peyer micro and bi
来源我们在Peyer micro和bi中
server is that you can send or provide a
服务器是您可以发送或提供
config source from one of your
来自您其中之一的配置源
applications into or send send the
申请发送或发送
configuration to the cluster from one of
从以下任一配置到群集
your nodes and then is available to all
您的节点，然后对所有人可用
the nodes because it's evenly
节点，因为它是均匀的
distributed with this class cluster
随该类集群一起分发
scoped being that it's more complex
范围在于它更复杂
because you need to synchronize and make
因为您需要同步并进行
sure that the data is only once there
确保数据仅存在一次
and hisoka's also provides locking
而Hisoka也提供锁定
mechanisms and synchronization
机制与同步
primitives so we we only needed to put
原语，所以我们只需要放
all these things together to provide
所有这些东西一起提供
things for the Java EE API because hazel
Java EE API的事情，因为榛树
Kyle is not to it it doesn't know about
凯尔对它不了解
Java EE so we essentially want to do and
Java EE，因此我们本质上想做
what we are doing and Empire is bringing
我们在做什么，帝国正在带来
all this excellent features of hazel
榛树的所有这些出色功能
cast to the level where it can be easily
投射到可以轻松实现的水平
accessed from Java EE applications
从Java EE应用程序访问
it's the same with Syria even bus we are
叙利亚甚至公共汽车都一样
using helices topics and as Acosta
使用螺旋主题和作为Acosta
queues to distribute the data that's the
排队分发数据
the API is very simple it's just two
API非常简单，只有两个
qualifiers and the same with the CDI
限定词与CDI相同
scope is just one called one
范围只是一个
scope annotation and it provides these
范围注释，它提供了这些
things base or handle cast and
事物的基础或处理方式
synchronization okay any other questions
同步好吗其他问题
no I think well thanks again for bearing
不，我想很好，再次感谢您的支持
with us we got through it just about
和我们在一起，我们几乎可以度过它
yeah I think we've actually got a demo
是的，我认为我们实际上有一个演示
that's sort of similar to this on the
这有点类似于
payara stand in the exhibition hall so
payara站在展厅里
if you want to kind of come and see
如果你想来看看
something that's actually uses raspberry
实际使用树莓的东西
pies as well you do drop by
馅饼，你也来
[Applause]
[掌声]